Better healthcare facilities are becoming more expensive over time. This
also needs to be considered when planning for retirement. Given the
lack of social security in India, having a
regular income is crucial. Therefore,
invest your retirement funds wisely. A
pension plan is
a way to earn a regular income even after retirement. This
plan is ideal for those
nearing retirement or already retired,
as it acts as a hedge
against market fluctuations and falling interest rates.
HDFC
Life has launched a standard pension plan called the Saral
Pension Plan, which
pays an immediate pension from the time of retirement with a guaranteed return for life.
This pension will be lifelong, and there is no
maximum limit on the amount that can be invested. This is
a non-participating single premium
plan, which can be opted for by those between 40 and 38 years of age.
This policy
offers flexible terms and conditions, which can be availed quarterly, half-yearly,
or on anniversaries. Among
its key features, there's a
single premium payment option.
This plan gives life long guaranteed income.
No medical examination is required under this plan.
In case of serious illness, you also get the option of surrender.
Under this plan, return of purchase price
is given on the date of launch. For this,
you are given high vesting and policy
loan facility is also available. Under this plan,
friends, Anti Corruption Helpline
offers two options - Lifetime pension with return of purchase price
and secondly,
return of premium on the date of last survivor in joint life. Saral Pension Plans are
extended plans in which all the
insurance features are also similar.
In this plan, the buyer of option A will
get lifetime validity. In case of death, the
entire purchase price will be paid to the nominee or legal officer.
Under option B, the amount will be payable as long as at
least one of the two is alive.
100% of the original amount is given to the co-contract holder for the lifetime from the date of primary insurance or thereafter.
On the death of the husband or wife, the
premium paid will be returned normally or to the legal officer. Let us
talk about friends.
So a man of one year puts ghee in ₹5,
friends, he will get a monthly pension of ₹10.
Subscribe 2176 appointed for women of 554
Friends, experts say
that usually a person gets an appointment
of ₹5000 under immediate initiative
and ₹21.50 for ₹10000 monthly pension. If we
talk about this plan, then
friends, it is 5.10.
Talking about the loan, then friends,
after 6 months of purchasing this plan, you can be given a loan on the policy.
If we talk about tax on the plan,
friends, then the pension is 1 table amount,
friends, hence tax will be levied according to this Vikram text loop. So
friends,
how did you like the information about HDFC Life Liquid Pension Plan, do write in the comment box. If you have any
questions related to the video, then you
can ask and do
not forget to subscribe to our channel for these investment options.
Thank you.